Inventory of the Gregory G. Shinkarenko papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Gregory G. Shinkarenko papers
1910-1942
95005
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (1.8 linear feet)
Writings, translations, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to Russian émigré life, fictional and historical writing by Russian émigrés (especially regarding Russian naval history), and the right-wing Russian émigré party Mladorosskaia Partiia.
Shinkarenko, Gregory G.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian-American translator.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, translations, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to Russian émigré life, fictional and historical writing by Russian émigrés (especially regarding Russian naval history), and the right-wing Russian émigré party Mladorosskaia Partiia.
Mladorosskaia partiia.; Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Russia--History, Naval.; Russian literature.
- Correspondence, 1925-1938
  - General, 1926-1931 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Benklevskiĭ (Benklevsky), A., 1927-1928 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Brasol, Boris (Brasol', Boris), 1927 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Bouliguin (Bulygin), Pavel Petrovich, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes writings.
  - Cederholm (Tsedergol'm), Boris Leonidovich, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Nemirovich-Danchenko, A., 1928 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Rozonoer, Nikolai Il'ich, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Semenov, Evgenii Petrovich, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Writings, circa 1925
  - “Na otvet 'tovarishcha' Iv. Kedrovskogo odnomu iz malykh, Voznesenskomu,”, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Mladorosskaia partiia file, 1928-1942
  - General, 1928-1939 (Box-folder 1: 10-14)
    Includes newsletters, memoranda, and writings.
  - Printed matter, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
    Includes brochures, bulletins, and newspapers.
- Writings by others, 1910-1929, undated
  Includes original manuscripts. Arranged by author.
  - Unidentified authors, undated
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - “The Epoch of Sail,”, undated (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - “In the Vldamir Monomachos,”, undated (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - "Predskazanie,", undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Benklevskiĭ ( Benklevsky), Anthony J., 1927 and undated
    - "History of the Formation of East African Colonies,", undated (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - "By Caravan,", 1927 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - "Na Sambuk,", 1927 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Chernomor, "Volny Baltiki,", undated (Box-folder 1: 21-24, Box-folder 2:1-3)
  - Chernomortsev, undated
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - "U beregov Antalii,", undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Enge, "Kazachestvo v morskikh pokhodakh,", undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Fedoroff (Fedorov), D., book review, "Tsusima," by A. Novikoff (Novikov)-Priboi, 1927 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Gordenev, M., undated
    - "The First Naval Victory of the Russian Fleet,", undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - "Za amerikanskim rubezhom,", undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Kube, M.O., Von, undated
    - "Chevalier Lombard,", undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - "Death of a Ship,", undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "The Tzar's Provider,", undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Loukin (Lukin), A., undated
    - "Lightning,", undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - "Uprising Aboard the Aurora,", undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Lubie (Liubi), C. de La, undated
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Lightning..Lightning..Lightning,", undated (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Monastyrev, N., undated
    - “Lieutenant Golovin and his Diana,”, undated (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - “To the South,”, undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Nikitin, D.V., "The Sea Roads to Constantinople,", undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Shchepot'ev, "Pamiatka gvardeiskogo ekipazha,", 1910 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Staniukovich, K.M., "The Shore and the Sea,", undated (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Viren, P., Von, "Poslednie dni russkoĭ eskadry v Biserde. Gibel' kanonerskoĭ lodki Groznyĭ,", undated (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Various authors, Morskoĭ zhurnal, articles, Prague, 1929 (Box-folder 2: 22)